<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Usage on Nodemailer</title>
    <link>https://nodemailer.com/usage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Usage on Nodemailer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:20:55 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nodemailer.com/usage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SMTP? Say what?</title>
      <link>https://nodemailer.com/usage/why-smtp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:44:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nodemailer.com/usage/why-smtp/</guid>
      <description>You might wonder why you would need to set something up while in comparison PHP&amp;rsquo;s mail command works out of the box with no special configuration whatsoever. Just call mail(&amp;hellip;) and you&amp;rsquo;re already sending mail. So what&amp;rsquo;s going on in Node.js?
The difference is in the software stack required for your application to work. While Node.js stack is thin, all you need for your app to work is the node binary, then PHP&amp;rsquo;s stack is fat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Gmail</title>
      <link>https://nodemailer.com/usage/using-gmail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:25:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nodemailer.com/usage/using-gmail/</guid>
      <description>Even though Gmail is the fastest way to get started with sending emails, it is by no means a preferable solution unless you are using OAuth2 authentication. Gmail expects the user to be an actual user not a robot so it runs a lot of heuristics for every login attempt and blocks anything that looks suspicious to defend the user from account hijacking attempts. For example you might run into trouble if your server is in another geographical location – everything works in your dev machine but messages are blocked in production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delivering bulk mail</title>
      <link>https://nodemailer.com/usage/bulk-mail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:40:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nodemailer.com/usage/bulk-mail/</guid>
      <description>Here are some tips how to handle bulk mail, for example if you need to send 10 million messages at once.
 Use a dedicated delivery provider. Do not use services that offer SMTP as a sideline or for free (that&amp;rsquo;s Gmail or the SMTP of your homepage hosting company) to send bulk mail – you&amp;rsquo;ll hit all the hard limits immediately or get labelled as spammer. Basically you get what you pay for and if you pay zero then your deliverability is near zero as well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
