<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nodemailer</title>
    <link>https://nodemailer.com/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nodemailer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 21:25:35 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nodemailer.com/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration</title>
      <link>https://nodemailer.com/about/migrate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 21:37:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nodemailer.com/about/migrate/</guid>
      <description>This migration document applies Migrating from Nodemailer 2 to Nodemailer 3 and to a lesser extent to 4
 Nodemailer v3 has dropped some features that were available in Nodemailer v2 and also introduced some new ones.
 All dependencies were dropped. There is exactly 0 dependencies needed to use Nodemailer. This brings the installation time of Nodemailer from NPM to less than 2 seconds All templating is gone. It was too confusing to use and to be really universal a huge list of different renderers would be required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://nodemailer.com/about/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 21:37:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nodemailer.com/about/license/</guid>
      <description>Nodemailer v4+ is licensed under the MIT license.
Version 3 of Nodemailer used the European Union Public License 1.1 which is a copyleft license. You can read about the reasoning behind using EUPL for Nodemailer from the Nodemailer blog. After a two months long experiment I decided to cancel all active subscriptions of Nodemailer and changed the license back to MIT.
Keeping a lower level infrastructure module under a restrictive license has turned out to cause more trouble than gains – I myself had to use older versions of Nodemailer for some client work to avoid any licensing conflicts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>