<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nodemailer</title>
    <link>https://nodemailer.com/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nodemailer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 21:25:35 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nodemailer.com/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Migration</title>
      <link>https://nodemailer.com/about/migrate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 21:37:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nodemailer.com/about/migrate/</guid>
      <description>This migration document applies to migrating from Nodemailer 2 to Nodemailer 3, and to a lesser extent, to Nodemailer 4.
 Nodemailer v3 introduces several changes, removing some features from v2 and adding new functionality to improve the overall experience.
Major Changes in Nodemailer v3  Zero Dependencies: All external dependencies have been removed, reducing the installation time to less than 2 seconds from NPM. Templating Removed: Templating support was dropped as it caused confusion and would have required extensive support for multiple rendering engines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://nodemailer.com/about/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 21:37:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nodemailer.com/about/license/</guid>
      <description>Nodemailer v4+ is licensed under the MIT license.
Version 3 of Nodemailer was licensed under the European Union Public License 1.1 (EUPL), which is a copyleft license. For more details on the decision to use EUPL for Nodemailer v3, you can refer to the Nodemailer blog. However, after a two-month experiment, I decided to revert Nodemailer back to the MIT license and canceled all active subscriptions.
Using a restrictive license for a lower-level infrastructure module like Nodemailer proved to be more problematic than beneficial.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
